<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project>
    <university>New Jersey Institute of Technology</university>
    <college>Ying Wu College of Computing</college>
    <course>
        <name>CS 631 Data Management Systems Design</name>
        <professor>Ravneet Kaur</professor>
    </course>
    <team>
        <member>Abhishek Mallikarjuna Maganalli</member>
        <member>Aditya Patel</member>
        <member>GuruKiran Reddy Kasireddy</member>
        <member>Kunlek Tenzing Tamang</member>
    </team>
    <introduction>
        Sports analytics is the art and science of gathering data about athletes and teams to create insights that improve sports decisions, such as deciding which players to recruit, how much to pay them, who to play, how to train them, how to keep them healthy, and when they should be traded or retired. For teams, it involves business decisions such as ticket pricing, as well as roster decisions, analysis of each competitor’s strengths and weaknesses, and many game-day decisions.
    </introduction>
    <background>
        In this project, we will be addressing the issues in the Sports Analytics industry, particularly in the Soccer industry. In all of the leading soccer leagues and divisions, the teams buy, sell, and loan players in 2 transfer windows ie. summer and winter transfers based on the player stats. A lot of effort goes into these transfer windows by different teams in scouting for players, preparing bids, and competing with other teams to sign the players. We are addressing this scenario by collecting the soccer player stats and providing comprehensive analytics to teams to make better decisions and make the transfer windows more efficient.
    </background>
    <objectives>
        <objective>Main objective of this project is to focus on the relational database component of universal athlete contract which includes:</objective>
        <sub-objectives>
            <entity-relation-diagram>The actual Database schema</entity-relation-diagram>
            <queries-and-population>Run queries and populate small data in our systems</queries-and-population>
            <other-features>Any other features that demonstrate our database understanding, such as stored procedures, triggers, etc.</other-features>
        </sub-objectives>
    </objectives>
    <scope>
        Our project's scope is centered on addressing challenges and inefficiencies within the Sports Analytics industry, with a particular focus on the soccer sector. The scope encompasses the following key areas:
        <areas>
            <data-collection-and-analysis>Data Collection and Analysis</data-collection-and-analysis>
            <decision-support>Decision Support</decision-support>
            <compensation-negotiations>Compensation negotiations</compensation-negotiations>
            <roster-management-and-scouting>Roster Management & Scouting</roster-management-and-scouting>
            <efficient-transfer-windows>Efficient Transfer Windows</efficient-transfer-windows>
        </areas>
    </scope>
    <emerging-possibilities>
        <possibilities>
            <expand-to-other-sports>Expand it to other sports (currently we are focusing only on the football aspect of it)</expand-to-other-sports>
            <make-project-live>Make this project go live (basically add a functioning front-end to it and link it to the database using any scripting language like PHP/Python)</make-project-live>
            <integrate-machine-learning>Integrate machine learning techniques to provide better insights and predictions about the player.</integrate-machine-learning>
        </possibilities>
    </emerging-possibilities>
</project>
